Diana Rocío Galindo González

34 641 87 34 52 08028 - Barcelona (Spain) **Indog@gmail.com in drgalindog **0 drgalindog**

Languages CEFR Spanish (MT) English C1 MSc student in data science with interest in developing analytics and data management projects. Background and experience in applied research and innovation projects for production and exploitation of georeferenced data and data analysis inference using statistical, machine Learning and AI algorithms methods.

Tools and languages for data analysis R, Rstudio (Advanced), Python, Jupyter (Medium)

Pandas, scikit learn, matplotlib (Medium)

SQL,Neo4J

Geospatial data analysis ArcGIS, QGIS, R, Rstudio, Geopandas, PostGIS, Leaflet, ERDAS, GRASS

Other tools Linux, LATEX

modelling

Other Courses
2019: Deep Learning
Big Data: Storage
and large volumes of
data
2018: Machine
Learning and Data
Science
2012: Agent-based

Education

2021–Currently MSc in Data Science 48/120 credits

Universidad Politécnica de Catalunya

2011–2013 M.Sc. in Geospatial Technologies

University of Muenster - Universidade Nova de Lisboa

2009–2010 Specialist in Statistics

Universidad Nacional de Colombia

2000–2006 Cadastral Engineer and Geodesist

Universidad Distrital Francisco José de Caldas

Professional experience

2020 - 2021 National Geographic Institute of Colombia - IGAC

Lead institutional research in geospatial technologies and geographic information management policies and the National Spatial Data Infrastructure of Colombia (ICDE) and the multipurpose cadastre.

Spatial Data Infrastructures, Machine Learning, Deep Learning, Earth Observation More information: Investigaciones 2020 and ICDE Colombia

2018 & 2020 National Department of Statistics in Colombia - DANE

Research and Development projects oriented to statistical and geographic information integration and explotation in Geostatistics Direction.

Spatial analysis, Machine Learning, Clustering, PCA, Data Visualization, Webscrapping.

2019 - 2020 Cadastral administrative Unit of Bogota

Geographic information management policies related to multipurpose cadastre and real state data.

Real state valuation and public policy, Geospatial Data management and integration

2015-2017 Colombian Agency for reintegration and normalization - ACR

Analysis of spatio-temporal information associated to ex-combatants reintegration processes

Spatial analysis and risk modelling

2013 - 2015 Ingecontrol S.A., Gestión Integral de Proyectos SAS and Indra Sistemas

Design and implementation of Geoprocessing Tool associated to Early Intervention in territory for HSE and Operational Sustainability Vice Presidency of Ecopetrol S.A.

Spatial analysis and geoprocessing, data integration and management

2010 - 2011 National Department of Statistics in Colombia - DANE

Updating census information related to housing using satellite data imagery and alternative information sources

Earth Observation data analysis, Spatial analysis and geoprocessing, data integra-

2007 - 2010 National Geographic Institute of Colombia - IGAC

Orthorectification of satellite images and aerial photographs and Edition, structuring of geographic information for official cartography of Colombia

Earth Observation data analysis, Cartography

Scholarships and achievements

2013 Universidade Nova de Lisboa

Best student of the MSc program in Geospatial Technologies during the 2011-2012 school year at ISEGI

2011 University of Muenster - Ministry of Innovation, Science and Research

NRW

MSc Scholarship in Geospatial Technologies

2006 Universidad Distrital Francisco José de Caldas

Meritorious Bachelor Degree Project

Publications

2019 Applied Spatial Analysis and Policy

Statistical and Spatial Analysis of Census Data for the Study of Family and Industrial Farming in Colombia

2013 13th International Multidisciplinary Scientific GeoConference, SGEM2013

Merging multispectral and pancromatic bands of Landsat using cok-

riging

2010 XX Simposio Colombiano de Estadística

Obtención del mapa de cobertura del páramo del Sumapaz